The first thing I notice is um your
size. Yes, sir.
>> How often does that come up when you're
just kind of walking around in the mall
or something?
>> A lot. I mean, I get I get stairs. I get
I get I get looks wherever I go. It
doesn't matter. And it's like, "Oh, oh,
you got to do something." So So
sometimes I I kind of just lie to them
and I'll be like, "Yo, I don't do
anything. I don't I don't know what
you're talking about." Like they they
ask if I play football. I said, "No, I'm
just a just a normal student here at
Alabama. I don't know why you're asking,
but
>> how do you use how do you use it to your
advantage down the field?
>> You know, with with me being bigger, I
mean, you're obviously expected to go
out there and and play, you know, fast
and physical with with power, and that's
kind of what I pride myself on. Um
because I know I know my talents and I
know my strengths, you know, is that
power, and I have good feet and, you
know, good hands. Um, so I know that I
can move anybody off the ball that I
want to, you know, when the when the
technique comes. So, what was it like
growing up being bigger than all the
other kids?
>> It was I It was definitely tough. You
know, I ain't going to lie. I was, you
know, when I was younger, it was I
wouldn't say it was like bullying or or
anything like that, but, you know, I was
always the bigger, you know, chunk of
your kid, so everybody's going to, you
know, try to make laugh and make fun of
you, but it's all right. You know, I got
the last laugh now.
>> Kaden, tell me about your personality
because I I get some um a good sense of
humor. I get uh a good sense of
commitment and work ethic also and some
of the toughness that Sully and Half
have talked about. Tell me about your
personality. How do you describe
yourself?
>> I I definitely try to be you know the
most most personable guy that I can be
and you know build relationships and and
have great communication. Um especially
you know in the in the team environment
that you know that's how you win
championships is uh really just being a
tight-knit close group. Um but also like
I said crack jokes and just have fun. I
mean, you only get one life, so you
know, you got to live it to the fullest.
>> Tell me about um I guess resiliency,
toughness. I I read that you had allowed
12 sacks as a freshman. Yeah.
>> But then you come back and you're a
first round pick, sir.
>> Tell me about the mental toughness, the
physical commitment to turn that around
like that.
>> Man, it just took a lot. I mean, I just
took longer to really grasp it and, you
know, kind of understand that, you know,
you got to leave, you know, some of the
outside factors, whether it's girl,
whether it's family problems, whether,
you know, it's different things, you got
to leave that outside the facility and
once you get there, it it's straight
work. So, kind of had to figure that
out. It took me a minute um you know, up
until mid-season of my freshman year to
really figure that out. But, ever since,
you know, I kind of got that in check.
Um, I feel like I've been, you know,
playing way better. Um, but all I can
say is, you know, you're I'm I'm 17
years old playing in the SEC. I'm I'm is
way different competition, but um yeah,
it's really about it.
>> What have the past whatever hours been
like for you since you got the call?
>> Oh, it's been wild. I mean, I've been
I've been running around doing different
media, been been up. I'm I'm running off
of three hours of sleep, but it's a it's
all worth it, you know, at the end of
the day. um got that call and my my my
chest started, you know, it started
pumping a little bit. Um I said before
all like in the interviews before the
draft that I wasn't nervous or didn't
have any butterflies in my stomach, but
once that first, you know, that call
came, yeah, it it just a rush of
emotion, you know, came over me and just
kind of started balling. I'm not
somebody that cries a lot, but I've been
a little I've been a little on the
softer side after after that happened.
I'm not going to lie. John Eric
Sullivan, the new GM here, is big on
high character guys. What do you think
are some of the things you showed him uh
that left an impression on on him?
>> I would say just yeah, really just being
personable and really being myself. You
know, I think
>> I I came into the combine with, you
know, predetermined answers to the
questions that I thought I was going to
get asked, but after a couple
interviews, I learned that you just got
to be yourself. And like I'm going I'm
going to cuss like that. I don't know.
That's is that's who I am. I I really
can't control it. I mean, it's just a
part of my me and my personality and how
I talk. Um, so I'm not g I'm not gonna
change myself for anybody. Um, so that's
really how I think. Yeah.
>> And I meant that.
>> What do you think is the key to reaching
your full on potential?
>> Really just honing in and focusing and
being the best learner that I can be,
you know, being around older guys that
have been there and done that. um really
just kind of sitting down and learning
that I'm the rookie. I got to I have
things that I need to work on. I'm not
the best player on the team, but you
know, I'm I'm I'm definitely going to
build myself up to be, you know, that
reliable, you know, reliable player if
if I'm out there on the field playing.
I'm trying to be the best guy that I can
be, you know, so that our team can go
succeed. As you got more comfortable at
the combine with the interviews, is it
safe to assume that the Dolphins were
not the first interview you had there?
>> Yeah, they weren't. They weren't they
weren't the first one. I I'm not going
to lie, I can't remember what what
number it is cuz I had like 20 formal
interviews and then like 10 more um
informal interviews. So, I I pretty much
talked to to the whole league um by the
time it was all said and done. But yeah,
it it only took me like two or three um
really that first night. I had three the
first night and then I had 15 16 the
second second day all in a row, you
know, from like 8:00 a.m. to 11 11:30
p.m. So that it was tough.
>> How much pride do you take in effect
that you're this new regime's first ever
draft pick?
>> Um I mean it just means a lot to even
just be the the a first round pick like
that. That's hard to do. there's a small
percentage of guys that go to the NFL,
but even that, you know, be to be a
first round pick um to be one of 32.
Like, that's such a blessing. You know,
a lot I know a lot of people would love
to be in in my shoes and to and to be in
this position. So, you know, I'm
definitely blessed. Um and I take
advantage of all the opportunities that
I'm given.
>> How much do you know about how much do
you know about the games of the other
guys on this line like Patrick Paul,
Aaron Brewer, and what do you think you
guys can accomplish together? I know I
know that they're fast and and they and
they rip and run off the ball. I know I
know from watching film um with with old
line coach here that they they they rip
and run off the ball and and they they
want to establish the run game. Um so
that's that's something I can be excited
for is that's that's what I'm trying to
do is just trying to go smashmouth
football. Um, so yeah,
>> when we talked to you on Zoom last
night, you were talking about um how at
Alabama you had worked to get your
weight to a to a place where you uh
wanted it to be more so. What are some
lifestyle or regimen things that you've
done to get where you are now? And how
do you think that'll help you uh
maintain your ideal proate now?
>> Yeah, I really I really uh
want to say shout out to, you know, Ryan
Smith and you know, my nutritionist um
that that were Alabama because they
helped me a lot through that in that
process. Um, I I knew it was going to be
a hard process, but you know, Ryan
helped me with like, yo, you got to go
to Hotworks or or do something that you
find enjoyable instead of, you know, I I
didn't like walking on a treadmill seven
days a week for two months straight.
Like, that that was just not fun. So, I
found something in Hotworks that I
enjoyed going in there. Felt good to get
a nice sweat in. It's 130 degrees in
there and do a workout. It doesn't take
long. 15, 30 minutes and you're out of
there. You're done. Um, and that's
that's kind of how I lost 20 30 pounds
cuz I was I was going there, you know,
day in and day out. Um, and I was
finding success from it. Um, but I would
say another thing, not eating after 7:00
p.m. is probably the biggest thing. Um,
cuz you're not you're not giving your
body enough time to digest. Um, so I I
found out when I don't eat after 7:00
p.m. I come in I have a good weigh in
and it just felt good. Like I it just
started feeling good for me to have
great weigh-ins in the morning. So
>> you really have you really have 170
bottles of clone.
>> I'm not going to lie.
>> Since that Since that interview at SEC
media days,
I probably doubled it. I'm not going to
lie. I I have 330 340 bottles in in my
collection right now. Yeah, it's it's uh
it's a little wild. I I got Yeah, I got
a problem,
>> but that's a good problem to have. Yeah,
I ain't I ain't I ain't out doing other
things. So,
>> NI money money on that,
>> I would say. So, I' I've got I've gotten
some free bottles from it, so it's it's
definitely it's definitely good to be
out there and and have people know that,
you know, you love smelling good and
that they they want to send they want to
send you their product and it's always
good getting free stuff.
>> What's what's the papers,
>> man? I was so
last night for the draft I was wearing
um Clive Christian Blonde Amber and it's
just man I don't even know how to
explain it just smells like royalty.
So that that's that's probably one of my
top ones. And then Prisma perfumes
Amethyst I've gone through like two or
three bottles of that. Louis Vuitton
makes some good cologn. Um that's I have
the uh I think it's California Dreams on
today. Um, but we could go on and on and
and we could we could take up the whole
time talking about Colog if we wanted
to. So,
>> how did that start?
>> I really say both my dads kind of put me
on that. Um, you know, when I was
younger,
I mean, elementary school, middle
school, whenever they they'll I go in
their collection and and spray spray on
the bottle before I go to school. Um,
and it just felt good getting
compliments. So, I was like, I need I
need to continue that. And once I
started getting, you know, get getting
my own money, some NIL money from from
Bama, uh, I kind of just started that
collection up immediately. Um, and even
even got my roommate Wilin into it a
little bit more. So, we both got over,
you know, 100 200 bottles. So, it's
wild.
>> What's more fun to you, driving a
defensive lineman off the ball?
>> Yeah.
>> Downhill or getting out in space and
hitting a big block on the perimeter?
>> I would say both equally. I would say I
would say driving somebody off the ball.
Um because you got to you got to drive
them a little longer. Um and you know
that you're I would say for for instance
maybe you're blocking down on the four
eye. You know it's it's man versus man
mono emano and it's like who whoever's
got the best technique and and and the
greatest strength is going to win. So I
I I love doing them type of blocks and
that's kind of why we we ran a lot of
pinpull, you know, towards the end of
the season. So, I was the down block and
and they knew I was going to get that
cut off. Um, so that that felt really
good.
>> Invested in Malik Willis and yesterday
the GM told us they invested in you to
protect him.
>> Yep.
>> How do you approach that?
>> I mean, I'm going it's it's I'm going to
battle every day. I promise you that. I
mean, any any quarterback that I that
I've ever protected, that's it's got to
be the same mindset. Like, they're uh I
would say I'm going tell y'all a little
story. Like Coach Wolf, he was my
freshman offensive line coach. And every
day he'll come in if if in practice or
or like we're giving up like a sack to a
scout team guy or like mess up
something, he'll get on us and be like,
"Man, QBs are making 40 $50 million.
Hey, you're letting them get killed out
there." So it's like, that just stuck
with me. So it's like you don't like
they run a team, they run a show. So if
you're not protecting them, you're not
going to go win games. So yeah. Another
thing that Sully mentioned uh he liked
about you was your work ethic. Um and I
know there's a difference between work
ethic and what it takes to become a
firstround draft pick. Yeah.
>> Who first instilled drive and work ethic
in you and what have you had to overcome
to get here?
>> Yeah, I would probably say Ryan Smith
because I I never did too much
>> like 12 on on under, you know. I didn't
really do too much. I didn't have to
focus on too much. I was just kind of
going out there and playing the sport.
But once I kind of got up with him, you
know, and I was 13, 14, I was going in
there, you know, early mornings, um,
even even when I'm bored, like just just
go hit a workout, just go do something.
Go go go hits. That's that's why I've
been doing that cuz it's comfortable to
me because I've been doing it since 13,
14 years old. Um,
so yeah.
>> You had Jaylen Milro 24 Tai Simpson last
year. I'm curious, obviously Milro is a
little bit more mobile, right? Yeah,
>> I'm curious how does it change when
you're protecting a mobile quarterback
like Malik Willis is versus someone that
is uh you know not necessarily that much
of a
>> Hey, I ain't going to lie, don't get it
twisted. Hey, Tai, he's athletic and he
can scoot too. I promise you that. But I
mean with with with Milro, we we
definitely ran a lot of more Q runs and
it's just a different it's it's just a
change. You know, Tai's definitely more
of a pocket passer. So that it just it
just changes up. We're not we're
obviously not running a lot of Q runs.
we're using the running backs a little
bit more. Um, so and we definitely we
definitely dropped back pass a a lot
more, you know, with with Tai. Um, so
those are probably the biggest things
that I saw, but
>> got picked right after you as I'm sure
you probably had no idea you're
celebrating.
>> I was so excited. Yeah, I was I was
celebrating, but I kind of I kind of
heard his family celebrating the same
time that that my family was and I'm
like, "No, man. No way this going to
happen." cuz I I'm telling you, I've
been telling Tai that yo, you're going
to go first round and you're going to go
to the Rams. I promise you, you can ask
him. I promise you. Um, so just for that
to happen, it was it was a surreal
experience. Um, because I know I know
Tai wasn't, you know, was was thinking
of not going to the draft, but you know,
with with a little convincing, you know,
probably from his family, probably from
me and you know, coaches. I'm like,
"Bro, you're going to go first round. I
promise you that. I know that. I know. I
know the type of leader that he is." Um,
but I'm I'm just so happy for him. It
kind of sucks that, you know, we're on
we're on two two sides of the country. I
ain't going to see my boy, but I know
he's going to go over there and handle
business.
>> So, you called that?
>> N I N don't don't give credit to me, but
nah.
>> What do you think the the 95 degree
training camp practices might be like
down here?
>> I mean, I that's that's where I'm coming
from. That's I'm I'm coming from Alabama
with with the humidity. So, I mean,
that's what that's what I'm used to.
It's all good. That that's work. I love
sweating. Like I said, Hotworks. I love
sweating. I love I love the 130 degrees
170° saunas. Like, it just feels good to
me. So,
>> yoga, Pilates kind of.
>> Uh, Hotworks, you can do like a roll
like a row machine, you can do a
stationary bike, you can do yoga. Um,
>> but yeah. Yep.
I noticed in one of your draft photos
you had your hands crossed and you had
the years 1972 and 2005 tattooed on your
knuckles. What's the significance of
those two years to I can imagine 2005 is
your
>> Yeah, that's me. Young
>> um but 1972 is for my stepdad. You know,
he he's been in my been in my life the
the whole way through. Um you know,
help helped raise me, you know, been in
the house. I've been live with him my
whole life. So, you know, that's kind of
why I got that tattoo. Um, but also know
that y'all that's the uh that's a
championship here. So, I mean I I I
suppose it was meant to be.